Kibitou High School
Founder's
Festival
（麻耶）みんな
ケガをしないよう気をつけて！→
Everyone, make sure you don't get hurt.
実行委員の指示に従って
後片づけを進めてね
Follow the instructions of the committee officials, and let's get everything cleaned up.
（生徒達）はーい
Okay!
（響）創設祭も無事終わったわね
Looks like we had another successful Founder's Festival.
今年のおでんも
水泳部伝統の味だったって
We even got a certificate from the alumni saying that our Oden maintained its traditional flavor this year.
ＯＢの方達から
お墨付きが　いただけて
ホッとしたわ
（逢）はい
That's a relief.
Yes.
七咲　このレシピを
あなたに託そうと思うの
Nanasaki, I'm thinking of giving this recipe to you.
Girl's Swim Club
Oden Stall Recipe
Secret Formula!!
えッ　２年生の先輩じゃなくて
私にですか？
To me?  Not one of the juniors?
ええ
あなたに受け取ってほしいの
Yeah.
I want you to have it.
あの大根の味は　すばらしかったわ
The Daikon you cooked was delicious.
No... it was no match for your Konbu, Senpai.
そんな
先輩の昆布には　かないません
七咲　あなたが
このレシピを引き継いで
Nanasaki, I want you to take this recipe and maintain the traditional flavor of the Swim Club from now on.
これからも水泳部伝統の味を
守り続けてちょうだい
I understand, Senpai.
分かりました　先輩
（拍手）
Ai-chan, make sure you prepare lots of the Chikuwa that I love next year.
（はるか）逢ちゃん
来年も私の大好物のちくわを
たくさん　仕込んでおいてね
それを楽しみに響と来るから
I'll look forward to it when I come with Hibiki.
私は来るかどうかは
分からないわよ
I don't know if I'll come next year.
そんな～　ちくわ食べに来ようよ
Come on...
Come and eat some Chikuwa with me!
フフッ
（琉璃子）りほっち
そっちは終わったかい？
Rihocchi.
Are you all done there?
（梨穂子）はーい
だいたい片づきました
Yes, I'm just about finished.
・（琉璃子）よし！
All right.
今年も　もう終わりだね
It's almost the end of this year.
そうですねえ
ホント→
Yes.
Time really does fly.
時のたつのが
早くなっていくなあ
ホントに…　そうですね
Yes, it really does.
・（琉璃子）うんじゃ
行くとするか
Well, let's get going.
ついておいで
Come with me.
うん？
・～
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaetara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたら
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
Nando mo kisetsu wo kasaneta ne ano hi kara
The seasons have come and gone since that day
何度も季節を重ねたね　あの日から
Kyou made doumo arigatou
And even today, I remain so grateful
今日までどうもありがとう
Semai rojiura mezashi
We head towards a narrow back alley
狭い路地裏目指し
Shiroi iki ga odoru
As our white breaths dance in the air
白い息が踊る
Itai kurai nigitta te wo hiite
You hold me by the hand so hard it almost hurts
痛いくらい握った手をひいて
Kimi wa susunde yuku
And pull me with you as you walk on forward
君は進んでいく
Ima sugu kisu shitakatta
I wanted to kiss you right then
今すぐキスしたかった
Kakureta jihanki no ura
Hidden behind the vending machines
隠れた自販機の裏
Hanikande mitsumeatta
We shyly gazed at each other
ハニかんで見つめあった
Yasashii kimochi afureta
And I was overcome with kind feelings for you
優しいキモチ溢れた
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaeta nara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたなら
Futari wa hitotsu da yo
The two of us would become one
２人は１つだよ
Donna chiisa na shiawase mo
No matter how small it may be
どんな小さな幸せも
Mitsukedaseru ki ga suru yo
We'll surely find happiness
見つけ出せる気がするよ
Yasashiku nareta no wa kimi no okage
I learned to be kind because of you
優しくなれたのは　君のおかげ
あれ　純一　何でここに？
Huh?
Junichi, why are you here?
Because Senpai asked me to come.
（純一）「何で」って…
先輩に呼ばれたから
It's to thank him for helping us out.
手伝ってくれた　お礼だよ
青空の下で飲むお茶も
いいもんだろう？
Isn't drinking tea under the blue sky like this pretty nice?
風流ってやつですね
It feels really refined.
うんうん　そうそう
Yeah, it does!
（風が吹く）
（愛歌）風流を味わう
その道は厳しい
The road to refinement is difficult.
Well, it's better than doing this on a blazing hot summer day.
まッ　夏に炎天下でやるよりは
マシじゃないかな？→
それと　わざわざ外で
やる面倒なところに→
Plus, don't you feel the elegance from going through the trouble to have it outside?
Sakurai Rihoko Arc
Chapter 3
Succession
風情を感じないかい？
クション！
The road to appreciating elegance is difficult.
風情を愛でる
その道は厳しい
確かに　そうかも
You're probably right.
ああ　やっぱり
おコタは天国ですね
Ahh, the kotatsu is just like heaven.
りほっち
コタツに根が生えちゃうぞ
Rihocchi, any more and you'll be rooted to it.
エヘヘ…
So you guys have open-air tea ceremonies from time to time?
野点って　たまにやるんですか？
Yeah.
うん　春先にも
新入生の勧誘でやってるんだよ
We also do one at the start of spring to attract new members.
へえ　知らなかったな
Wow, I never knew.
・（琉璃子）地味だから　新入生も
そうそう見にこなくてね→
It's not very exciting, so we don't get many visits.
しかも　去年は
雨で中止になったんだよ→
We also had to cancel it last year because it rained.
せっかく用意したお菓子が
余って余って…
The snacks we prepared got left over...
それはまた　大変でしたね
That must have been tough...
・（琉璃子）まあ
そこの唯一の新入部員が→
Well, our only new member over there took care of that problem easily.
きれいに
処分してくれたんだけどさ
エヘヘ
I see...
なるほど
Thank you very much.
どうも　ありがとうございます
野点　僕はいいなって思いましたよ
Open-air tea ceremonies are quite nice.
だろう？
Right?
I was thinking it'd be even better if we had some music to go with it.
あと　音楽でも流れてれば
なお　いいかなって…
Ah, but I guess that interferes with enjoying the outdoor atmosphere.
でも　自然を楽しむってのとは
違いますよね？
アハハ
Music...
音楽…
音楽か
Music, huh?
あんた　いいこと言うね
うん！
That's pretty clever!
Yeah, you're right.
そうだなあ　来年からは
そうした方が　いいかもな
Maybe we should start doing that next year.
名案
吹奏楽部あたりに頼んで→
Good idea.
Should we ask the Wind Instruments Club if they want to recruit with us?
一緒に　やってみようか？
ああ　いいですね
Ah, that sounds good.
頼んだよ　りほっち
We're counting on you, Rihocchi.
We'll come visit next year.
私達　来年も見に来るからさ
はい
Yes!
I see.
そうか　来年の春は
先輩達も卒業ですもんね
You'll both graduate next spring, right?
まあね
寂しくなっちゃうなあ
Pretty much.
It'll get lonely around here.
Don't worry!
大丈夫です！
I'll definitely keep the Tea Club going!
私が
茶道部を守ってみせますから！
（愛歌・琉璃子）おお～
All right, time to clean up.
さて　片づけますか
Oh?  So you have some interest in tea?
おや　お茶に興味がおありかな？
あれ？
やってみると結構　難しいですね
Huh?
It's actually a lot harder than it looks...
Right?
だろう？
Tea is a deep discipline.
茶道は奥深い
It's no good...
ダメだ　うまくいかない
I can't do it well.
You're hopeless.
しょうがないなあ
Junichi, want me to do it?
純一　私が代わろうか？
うん　頼むよ
Yeah.
フフン
先輩達と全然違うような…
That doesn't look like how they do it at all...
梨穂子は僕と
大して変わらなくないか？
Rihoko, you don't seem much better than me.
That can't be true!
さすがに　そんなことはないよ～
（一同　笑う）
じゃあ　先輩　失礼します
失礼します
Okay, Senpai.  Off we go.
We're going.
おう　気をつけてお帰り
Yeah, take care on your way home.
転倒注意
はーい　さような…
Don't fall over.
Yes, see you la-
あッ！
Ow...
H-Heavy...
イテテテ
重い
Are you okay?
（琉璃子）大丈夫か？
いやあ
Man...
言ってる先から見事に
期待に応えるなあ　りほっちは
You really live up to expectations, Rihocchi.
アハハ…
来年も　よろしくお願いしまーす
I'll count on you next year too.
ああ…
ごッ　ごめんね　純一！
S-Sorry, Junichi!
頑張れ　りほっち
Go for it, Rihocchi.
Thank you for cleaning up.
（詞）後片づけ　お疲れさまでした
茶道部のお茶会　大盛況でしたね
The Tea Club's event was a big success, wasn't it?
ありがとう
Thanks.
Sorry I caused so much trouble yesterday...
（麻耶）昨日は迷惑かけちゃって
ごめんなさいね
・（琉璃子）甘酒で
あんなに酔っ払うのは→
You're probably the only one who gets that drunk from sweet sake, Sensei.
先生くらいですよ
Ahh, how embarrassing.
いや～　面目ない
先生　来年は気をつけてくださいよ
Sensei, be careful next year, okay?
You need a lesson.
学習が必要
気をつけます
I'll be careful...
The committee president sure has her act together.
・（琉璃子）実行委員長は
しっかり者だね
りほっちのために
爪のアカが欲しい
Rihocchi should take a leaf out of her book.
ついでにヘソのゴマも
もらっとくか
She might as well take the whole book.
Yeah.
Merry Christmas!
（美也・紗江・逢）メリークリスマス！
・（美也）２５日に　なっちゃったけど
It's Christmas Day instead of Christmas Eve,
こうやって３人で
クリスマスパーティーができて　よかったね
but I'm glad the three of us can have a Christmas party like this.
（紗江）そうだよね
私と美也ちゃんは２日連続だね
I agree.
It's the second one in a row for Miya and me.
Thanks for doing this for me...
ありがとう　私のために
このケーキとお料理
中多さんが持ってきてくれたの？
Did you bring this cake and food, Nakata-san?
うん　今日も美也ちゃんちで
パーティーするって言ったら
Yeah.
When I told my dad we're having a party at Miya's place, he prepared it and told me to bring it with me.
お父さんが持っていきなさいって
用意してくれたの
すごいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing?
大きなケーキ
食べきれるかな？
What a big cake.  I wonder if we can finish it.
大丈夫
No worries there.
I have a spare stomach for cake!
ケーキは別腹だよ　にししし…
・（逢）昨日　２人から
プレゼントもらったから→
Both of you gave me a present yesterday, so I'm returning the favor today.
今日は私から２人にお返し
はい
Here.
・（美也）わあ～
・（紗江）ありがとう
Thank you!
あのさ　純一
今日　ちょっと時間ある？
Hey, Junichi.
Are you free today?
うん？
Um...
えっとね…
I know you're on a diet, but making me order alone...
いくらダイエットだからって
僕にだけオーダーさせて
水だけって…
You're just having water?
梨穂子も何か注文しろよ
You should order something too, Rihoko.
Well, I just ate a lot of snacks in the clubroom...
だってさ　さっき部室で
お菓子いっぱい食べちゃったから
I need to control myself...
控えないと…
何だよ　そんな目されたら
食べられないじゃないか
What?
I can't eat it if you keep staring at it.
えッ？
半分　食べていいぞ
You can have half.
ダメダメ　我慢するんだから
I can't!  I have to hold back!
だったら
そんな目でケーキを見るなよ
Then stop staring at my cake.
But...
だって…
（薫）フフッ
コーヒーのお代わりは　いかが？
Would you like some more coffee?
Ah, Kaoru.
あッ　薫
へえ　クリスマスもバイトか
Working on Christmas, huh?
大変だな
（薫）まあね→
Must be tough.
I guess so.
そのかわり　大みそかと元旦は
休ませてもらうつもりよ
But in exchange for that, I'm planning on having New Year's Eve and New Year's Day off.
毎年　３１日は
お母さんと一緒に大掃除して
Every year on the 31st, my mom and I clean up the house and prepare food for the New Year.
おせち料理の準備をして
で　午前０時になったら→
And when midnight arrives, we visit the shrine.
初詣でに行くことにしてるから
ふうん　そうなんだ
・（薫）うん
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Okay, enjoy.
じゃッ　ごゆっくりどうぞ
で　話って何だよ？
So what did you want to talk about?
あのね　純一
Well, Junichi...
It's about returning the favor for my last present...
この前のプレゼントの
お返しのことなんだけどさ
ああ　何か思いついたのか？
うん　えっと…
Oh, did you think of something?
Yeah.
Uh, um... well...
あの…　ね　初詣でに一緒に
行ってほしいかな
I want to go on a New Year's shrine visit with you... or something...
なんて…
Sure.
いいよ
ホント！？
Really?!
Yeah.
ああ　でも
そんなことでいいのか？
But are you sure that's all you want?
うん
Yeah.
Okay, come to my place at night on the 31st then.
じゃあ　３１日の夜　ウチに来いよ
うん！
Okay!
やっぱり　ケーキちょうだい
I guess I'll have the cake after all!
Yeah, go ahead.
ああ　どうぞ
う～ん　おいしい！
So good!
Oh, it's Kanae-san!
あッ　香苗さんだ！
えッ！
Kanae-chan?
香苗ちゃん？　どこどこ？
Where?
ほら　あそこ
Look, over there!
I'm sure Kanae-san would be upset if she saw her friend Rihoko eating cake when she's supposed to be on a diet...
香苗さん
ダイエット中のはずの梨穂子が
ケーキを食べてるところ見たら
怒るだろうな～
えッ　どこどこ？
ほら　あそこだよ
Uh... where is she?
Look, over there!
え～ッ　どこ～？
Where?!
ほら
Here.
Just kidding.
うそだよ
あ～ッ
Aw... Geez, Junichi!  All you do is lie!
もう純一ったら　うそばっかり
う～ん
あむ
あッ…
ふぇッふぇッふぇッ
H-Hey, Rihoko!
おッ　おい　梨穂子
What was that?
何だよ　こないだ
ダイエットに協力してくれって
Didn't you ask me to help you with your diet?
梨穂子が言ってたんじゃないか
う～ん　まあ　そうなんだけど
I guess I did...
今日　食べた分は
ちゃんと後で運動するから
I'll definitely work out for what I ate later...
うん！
Yeah.
はあ…
I'll exercise more than I usually do, so I'll be just fine.
いつもより　たくさん動くから
大丈夫　大丈夫
（電話のベル）
Phone, phone...
・（美也）電話　電話→
Beaver
Three Kingdoms
By
Beaver
Nii-nii, the phone's ringing!
にぃに　電話！→
電話だってば！　にぃに！
The phone, Nii-nii!
はーい　今　行くよ！
Okay, I'll go get it!
美也！　何だよ　その格好
Miya!  What's with that get-up?
I was in the middle of taking a bath!
お風呂の途中だったの！→
寒いから早くして
It's cold, so hurry up and get it!
Who is it?
誰から？
梅ちゃん
Ume-chan.
何だろう？
What could it be?
・（梅原）う～ん　いいねえ→
How nice!
・美少女が
俺からの電話に出るために
A pretty girl came out of the bath to pick up my phone call!
・お風呂から飛び出してきて
そしてバスタオルを…
And she's only in a bath towel...
切るぞ
Bye.
・あ～ッ　待て待て
Aw man, wait, wait!
・冬休み中に例の新作ビデオ
借りにいっていいか？
Can I come borrow that new video we were talking about for winter break?
Sure... when are you coming?
いいけど　いつ来る？
・大みそかとか　どうだ？
How about New Year's Eve?
・何だったら
そのまま大将のウチで
If anything, we might as well have a
viewing party right at your house, boss!
・お宝鑑賞会という流れでも
いいがな
We could pick out the porn video of the year or something...
・お宝オブ・ザ・イヤーの
選出ってのも　ありか
・あッ　あと　この前言ってた
新作シューティングゲームもやらせてくれ
Ah, and let me try that new shooting game you told me about.
悪い　大みそかはダメだ
Sorry, I can't on New Year's Eve.
梨穂子と
初詣でに行くことになってるんだ
I'm going for a shrine visit with Rihoko.
（梅原）何～ッ　この裏切り者！
What?!  You traitor!
・何がだよ？
What are you talking about?!
You're going for a shrine visit with Sakurai-san!
・何がって桜井さんと初詣でって
Since when did the two of you get that close?!
・お前　いつから
そんな仲になったんだよ！？
You're a horrible person to keep that from me...
・ひでえな
俺に黙ってるなんて
・冷てえなあ
You're so cold!
いや　だから何度も言うが
Well, I dunno how many times I've said this,
梨穂子は　ただの幼なじみだからな
but Rihoko is just a childhood friend.
・大将　知ってるか？
Boss, did you know?
・桜井さん
結構　人気あるらしいぜ
Sakurai-san is apparently pretty popular.
・男子から手紙もらったりして
She gets letters from guys and stuff...
へえ　そうなのか
Oh, really?
Happiness may be found at a place closer than you think.
・幸せってのは
意外に身近なところに
・あんのかもしれねえぞ
て…　俺今　結構詩人だったよな？
Wait... wasn't I quite the poet?
Well?  Wasn't that pretty clever?
どうだ
なかなか名言じゃねえか？
はいはい　ああ　そうだ
Yeah, right.
Oh, that's right.
Come over today if you're gonna.
来るなら今日　来いよ
There's something I want you to lend me too.
僕も
お前に借りたいものがあるんだ
Oh?
ほほう
・（香苗）ちゃんと誘えたんだ
So you actually asked him?
・やったじゃない　桜井
よかったね
Good job, Sakurai!
That's good.
うん　それはよかったんだけど
Yeah, that's good, but I also have some bad news.
残念なお知らせも　あるんだよ
・えッ　どうかした？
Huh?  What's the matter?
Entrance Ceremony
Well... there was this sweet cake, and...
実は　甘～いケーキを…
・食べちゃったの？
You ate it?!
Yeah, Junichi said I could have it, so I couldn't help it...
うん　純一が
くれるって言うから　ついつい…
・もう　ダメだなあ
Geez, you're hopeless.
でも運動は
ちゃんと　するつもりだよ
But I'm definitely gonna exercise!
食べたら動くって感じで
You know, working out for what you ate...
・うんうん　よし頑張れ　桜井
Okay.  Well, go for it, Sakurai.
うん！
Yeah.
にい…
Two...
Three...
さんッ！
うう…
うう…　目標　１００回
My goal is a hundred...
But it's impossible...
なのに　無理
はあ
純一と初詣でか
A shrine visit with Junichi, huh?
楽しみ
I can't wait...
（チャイム）
おーい　美也　出てくれ！
Hey, Miya!
Get the door!
（チャイム）
Miya, you there?
美也　いないのか！？
何だよ　仕方ないなあ
Geez, guess I'll get it.
はい　はーい
Coming!
ああ　美也
あッ
Oh, Miya.
何だ　梨穂子か
So it was you, Rihoko?
Nii-nii!
にぃに！
えッ？
あッ
わッ
わッ　ごめん
Sorry!
Geez, Junichi!
もう～　純一ったら
ずいぶん早く来たんだな
You came over pretty early.
うん　久々に美也ちゃんとも
ゆっくり話したかったし
Yeah, I wanted to have a nice chat with Miya-chan since it's been a while.
にししし…
Let's have some New Year's soba together!
一緒に年越しそばを
食べるんだよね～
Yeah!
ね～ッ
All right, it should be about done.
よし　そろそろ　いいかな？
おいしい！
だろ？
It's delicious!
Right?
（美也）最近　にぃにったらお茶を
入れてくれるようになったんだよ
Nii-nii keeps making the tea for us recently.
前は全然
そんなことしなかったのにね～
Even though he's never done anything like this before...
The Tea Club seniors taught me how to make good tea, and I kinda got addicted to it.
先輩達に　おいしいお茶の入れ方を
教えてもらって
ちょっとハマっちゃって
Junichi's tea might even be better than mine.
私より　純一の方が　うまいかも
The water temperature and steeping time are important.
お湯の温度と蒸らし時間が
大事なんだ
ここが　うまさのポイント
That's how you make good tea.
何よ　偉そうに
いいだろ
What are you showing off for?!
Does it matter?
Okay, okay.
はいはい　２人とも
つまらないことでケンカしないの
The two of you shouldn't fight over something that small.
そうそう　これ食べて
Oh yeah, have some of this.
I'm challenging myself to make new stuff!
新メニューに挑戦したんだよ
チーズスフレ！
Cheese soufflés!
・（美也）わあ～　おいしそう！
Wow, they look delicious!
チーズスフレ…
Cheese soufflés...
What happened to your dieting, Rihoko?
ダイエットはどうした　梨穂子？
I-I took care not to use too much sugar in these cheese soufflés!
こッ　このチーズスフレは　おッ　お砂糖を
控えめにしてあるんだよ
確か　チーズって
カロリーが高いんじゃないのか？
Doesn't cheese have a lot of calories?
えっと　えっと…
Uh, um...
Ah, it's delicious!
わ～ッ　おいしい！
おッ　ホントだ　これはイケる
Whoa, you're right.
This is really good.
Really?  I'm glad.
そう？　よかった～
Well, I'll have one too!
じゃあ　私も　いただきま～す
Doesn't the singing program on TV start soon?
・（美也）そろそろ
歌の番組が始まる時間だね
うん　うん
Yep, yep!
Who's the highlight of this year again?
今年のトリは誰だっけ？
Sabu-chan, obviously.
そりゃあ
サブちゃんに決まってるだろ？
（美也）ホントだ
へえ　そうなんだ
Ah, you're right.
Oh, I see.
そういえば　今年は
あのアイドルユニットが登場するね
That reminds me, that idol unit is
performing in this year's show, right?
楽しみ　楽しみ
I can't wait!
ほら！
Look!
美也ちゃんも好きなの？
Miya-chan, you like it too?
Yep, I do!
・（美也）うん　好き！
うん？
（梨穂子・美也）・～ラララ　ララ…
（梨穂子と美也が歌い続ける）
・～ラララ　ララ…
・～
わあ　梨穂ちゃん　カッコイイ！
Wow, Riho-chan!  You're so cool!
Yeah, that was pretty good.
うん　結構うまいじゃないか
Really?
そう？
にししし…
これはもう
２人でデビューするしかないかな？
Now the two of us will have to make our debut!
う～ん　デビューとかは　ちょっと…
I don't know about making a debut...
え～ッ　何で？
Huh?  Why?
I like singing, but I don't know about becoming an idol...
歌は好きだけど
アイドルになるのは　ちょっと…
Why not?
何でなんだよ？
Why not?  No real reason...
何でって　別に…
・（美也）あッ　始まるよ→
Ah, it's starting!
にぃに　テレビのリモコン貸してよ
Hey, Nii-nii, hand me the remote.
Don't you have it?
そっちにないのか？
え～ッ　ないよ
No, I don't.
That's because I definitely can't have New Year's Eves like this if I become an idol.
〈だって　アイドルになったら〉
〈きっと　こんなふうに
大みそかを過ごせないもん〉
さて　そろそろ行くか
Well, we should get going.
うん
でも美也ちゃん　寝ちゃったね
Yeah!
Miya-chan fell asleep though.
She's hopeless.
しょうがないな～
じゃあ　僕用意してくるから
Well, I'll go get ready, so could you wake Miya up for me?
梨穂子　美也を
起こしておいてくれないか？
Yeah, I will.
うん　分かった
美也ちゃん　美也ちゃん
Miya-chan.  Miya-chan.
ふあ～
よし　準備ＯＫ！
All right, I'm ready!
あッ
よし　準備ＯＫ
All right, I'm ready!
Huh?
えッ？
何だよ　ミイラ取りがミイラになって
どうすんだよ
Geez, what'll we do if the hunter becomes the hunted?
うんと…
きなこも　いいけどピーナツバターもなあ
Nnh... soybean flour is good too, but peanut butter might be...
Heh... snacks even in her dreams, huh?
て…　夢でも　お菓子なのか
I wonder if Sakurai is with Tachibana-kun around now?
（香苗）桜井は今頃
橘君と一緒かな？
（寝息）
あッ　寝ちゃったんだ
Ah, I fell asleep...
The shrine visit!
初詣で！　純一　美也ちゃん！
J-Junichi!  Miya-chan!
Wake up, wake up!  We slept in!
起きて　起きて！
寝坊しちゃったよ～
（美也）結構すいてて
よかったかも
It's probably a good thing there aren't many people around.
そうだな
日付が変わる前後に来ると
Yeah.
We'd probably have to wait in line for about an hour to pray if we came around midnight.
お参りするまでに
１時間くらい並んだりするもんな
そうだね
Yeah.
そういえば高校受験のときも
Oh yeah, didn't we also come here to pray for our high school entrance exams?
純一と一緒に
ここで合格祈願したね
うん
Yep.
梨穂子は
数学の問題を解いてる最中に
Rihoko, you'd always fall asleep in the middle of solving math problems.
いつも寝ちゃってたなあ
Rihoko, did you solve question 2 yet?
《梨穂子　問２できたか？》
《あッ？》
《ああ…》
That's right.
そうだったね　夏休みだったよね
It was during Summer break.
《ふう　ちょっと休憩》
Ah, time for a break.
In the end, I just kept getting distracted.
〈結局
気が散ってばっかりだったなあ〉
〈結局　食べてばっかりだったなあ〉
In the end, I just kept eating.
〈（純一・梨穂子）でも
合格できたってことは…〉
But... we still managed to pass...
Happy New Year
Here.
はい
何？
Happy New Year
Hmm?
Oracle
プレゼントのお返し
In return for your present.
ありがとう
願い事を書いて
Thanks!
They said to write your wishes on it and hang it over there.
あそこに　ぶら下げるんだってさ
Okay.
うん
What should I do...
どうしようかなあ
Have you decided what you'll write?
書くことは
決まってるんじゃないのか？
そっか
Ah, that's right...
I wish my diet will be successful
I wish new members will join the Tea Club
Rihoko
I wish my diet will be successful
I wish new members will join the Tea Club
にぃに　梨穂ちゃん！
おみくじ　引こうよ
Nii-nii!  Riho-chan!
Let's go draw our oracles!
Okay.
ああ
Okay, wait for me.
ちょっと待って
あッ！
やった～ッ　大吉
Yay!  I got "excellent luck"!
"Small luck".
小吉
私は末吉
I got "uncertain luck"...
勝ったな
So I win.
"Uncertain luck" and "small luck", I wonder which is better?
末吉と小吉は
どっちが運が　いいんだろう？
Well, "uncertain" means it might not happen, so isn't it the worst?
そりゃあ　末ってことは末だから
最後だろう？
末広がりの末だから
縁起いいんじゃないのかなあ
It could be "uncertain" as in "uncertain boundaries", so maybe there's no end to my luck.
・（美也）にししし…
Out of the way!
下がれ　下がれ
Lord "Excellent Luck" is coming through!
大吉さまのお通りだ～
What the heck is that?
何だよ　それは
Ah, they have Zenzai!  Let's have some!
TL Note: Zenzai is a thick, sweet red bean soup with mochi.
あッ　ぜんざいがあるよ
食べていこうよ
ぜんざいとは…
まッ　お正月くらいは　いいかな？
Zenzai...?
Well, I guess it's fine, since it's New Year's.
Huh?  What, Junichi?
えッ　何　純一？
梨穂子は
おもち抜きの　ぜんざいかな？
I wish my diet will be successful
I wish new members will join the Tea Club
Rihoko
Rihoko, you'll be having Zenzai with no mochi, right?
え～ッ　それは
ぜんざいとは言えないよ～
I wish my diet will be successful
I wish new members will join the Tea Club
I wish my feelings will reach him someday ♥
Rihoko
What?  It wouldn't be Zenzai then!
join the Tea Club
I wish my feelings will reach him someday ♥
Rihoko
エヘヘ…
・（美也）にしし…
・～
Kokoro ga kyunto
心がきゅんと
The area around my heart tightens
Sukoshi dake kyunto
少しだけきゅんと
Just a little bit
Shimetsukerareta nara
締め付けられたなら
Since it's tightening like this
Hontou no koi na no kana?
本当の恋なのかな？
Could this be true love?
Hikaru shibafu no ue
光る芝生の上
Didn't we use to play around
Fuzakete nekoronda ne
ふざけて寝転んだね
And lie down on the sunlit grass?
Mujaki datta
無邪気だった
We were so innocent
Osanakatta hibi
幼かった日々
During our childhood days
Demo kokoro no oku de
でも心の奥で
But deep in my heart
Sodatte yuku kanjou wo
育って行く感情を
A feeling was growing
Sukoshi zutsu kizukihajimeteta
少しずつ気づき始めてた
And I slowly came to realize it
Onaji toki wo sugoshita bun dake
同じ時を過ごした分だけ
The more time we spent together
Sunao ni narenakute
素直になれなくて
The less able I was to be honest
Toomawari shita
遠回りした
I did things indirectly
Kokoro de gyutto
心でぎゅっと
My heart tightens
Tonari de sotto dakishimete
隣でそっと抱き締めて
As you gently embrace me
Anata wo mitsumeteru yo
あなたを見つめてるよ
I can't take my eyes off you
Sore wa chiisana koi no hajimari
それは小さな恋の始まり
That's the beginning of this small love of mine
Ima wa mada ienai kedo
今はまだ言えないけど
I can't tell you this just yet
Anata ga suki da yo
あなたが好きだよ
But I love you
Preview
Next episode preview.
The New Year has finally arrived, Rihocchi!
Happy New Year.
Let's have a good year together!
Yeah, let's have a good year to-
Wait, we're graduating this year!
Oh, you're right.
Absentminded.
Get a grip now!
Next episode: "Farewell".
Next Episode
Farewell
I'd better get new club members...
Are new club members all you'll be getting?
Huh?
A darling.
Huh?!